Has a redoing...
So, thanks for coming in today shown up I'm brett...lead program manager for
...accessibility group inside windows operating system group and this is my colleague mr chris
anderson howdy.
And, today if you look up here ravel url...to connect
...and we've done this basically as an example of how can
we start extending accessibility...new ways to the lexicon project that one of our
developers did you go to this website to...looks.
Like powerpoint...subtly different into...it all the text is taken from the
middle layer...the back-end...this you can listen through
...listen...screenwriter more importantly depending
on your device if it's windows device or...device your device
choice you can connect to in participate...talk more about that as we go on through the session.
Right there's...feedback...feedback please let us know questions comments
...also...extensions for you so we can bring more and better information.
So,...this talk about accessibility and spent about probably seventy years
...my career talking about accessibility people thinking about it it's really want
to talk about what is accessibility any...have to do that
in context with a disability so spend some time talking about different classes
and disabilities...of possible...those are situational or data
day or maybe even tempered depending what's going on and then kind of why we do the work.
So, we'll talk about what motivates us why we like...going on.
...defect speaker so who are
...and what is accessibility team and what we think about the parts you think about everyday
...kind of walk...pieces for and then we're going to take a little journey
...focus on...because a lot of time they went unspoken developers or
that convene said hey look I don't know needs to really make and accessible for
...reader and the truth is it's really
...this is already in your head and to build a...and talk to and
app is pretty straightforward easy to do and sort of walked and then from there we're going to
live...with...and...kind of...you guys theater dance developers and we're
...look at the to common patterns that we
...people toknown understand and really?
...to fix and understand...people with the using people who...screeners.
So, we dive into the successfully for your app again...design for every designs are
...the design and really...writing...sketching a picture of it
...usually good at saying I click on a b happens of
interactive c and d happens so really you build this nice big-state diagram and
...only three step to consider which is a start state...
and...repeat that quite a bit and the talk...make more sense of go along and
at the end of it the beauty of...is...it turns out to be a fairly
...amount of code very small number of lines and
...go something is very accessible...be accessible on the...the desktop analysis
believable and...to where all of the windows universal platform...
So, when we think about what is a disability we think about a
...disabilities and these are some of them and not all of them but some...cognitive
...you have...need for less information because that's all you can process?
In some cases you need less information because it's too much stimulus overload
institute some cases
...studies with focus autism they find that the less type of data they have
a available to them action the better they are...function.
...learning disabilities people...even
...dyslexia orders calcium where you can't really process fright.
Process...equations.
But, the thing I learned disabilities there's always the flipside...are learning
ability so my case and low-vision I'm legally blind so I learned from really listening
really well so it's also about bringing data to someone...a way that they can
consuming whether it's through audio author visuals and look at visual impairments as a range of visual
impairments what...go through a few samples in the next slides.
There's motor impairments...about motor impairments is that there's a range of them anymore
...have parkinson's disease you may have trouble doing fine motor control.
...also be something more temporary you've broken error and you can't use it how do you
...the system or more recently a friend of mine had a little baby tommy is
...baby...the interact with the system.
That's kind...range of spectrum credibility impact and how people's lives?
...perception...text size of
the common thank you get older the ability to read small text decreases.
So, how do you help that I find that people...you might arms have gotten
...as I've gotten older I...I try to holdings farther and farther way
...part of this accessibility getting us to where we have longer arms
...ok great is...build adapt that because
excuse me because you're for it may be...need things larger?
...that you have color perception also so I spent quite
a time writing reports I put together...some...and some green and yellow and I put a
little excel spreadsheet I sent it out and probably ten minutes later
sever managers replied back and I said I'm color-blind accessibility
so it kinda have to think through the things of it was easy for all forget like
you get like said we still struggle with this with this particular manager is actually presenting tomorrow and,
he's red green color-blind...to this day years of working with...we still have...
wrong colors yes exactly and there's a combination of things color perception and
...text gets smaller and smaller...process
...contrast issues now we live in seattle not a lot
of sunny days.
But,...walking out in the
sun chinese my cellphone and suddenly all of data washes out and I find myself
...into a shadow to try to read to read interact my cellphone because...contrast...
...and that analogous
...when contrast goes to zero that could be because you have no
site or because of situations where you frankly relatively user site, yeah, so,
for example, I would argue that low-carb very low contrast as appropriate for text messaging and
cars yes software things should not be doing...driving.
And, then we have and it has been...have all what are some
...severe motor functions and really what can you do through
...technology so really what...accessibility...to us and we think about
it should about usability that connects lives in this case.
Steve's able to use has technology to communicate with
his family his wife and friends and in those simpler case today
or project...powerpoint out to your device allows me as a presenter to connect
...in the best possible allows someone with low-vision
...no vision to hear and...not miss what's going on
so really for us about how do we connect people through technology
certainly starts with you and how do we help you build and create a moreaccessible...
And, that really comes through things why do we want to
do it well for us again it's really about impacting people's lives
kind of maximizes if you're app...you're building applications for education or for the
workplace or just for fun it really allows everybody to kind of interaction
use application and flows are developers or pragmatic sometimes you
want test automation so how do I make sure I continue to build my app make sure works
...work...forward and frankly...doing it's kind of fun it's great to go out help people out
...think about different ways to really build interaction model between people.
...parts in the stack.
So, the top of courses always your app...a different frameworks
...can use you can use the
...framework web html framework wintry to if you like
...kind of flows down through some of the lower layers around url animation
...little time...animation because it really is the contract.
Is that the api set that actually says the
intent of your application so if, you know, you want something to work from button or list box?
...in a way that allows this...to have a read to someone or
...action on behalf of somebody.
And, if you look at throughout the sectors input pieces how do
you do input for those it can't move well how do you
render the text so it's easy-to-read for high contrast scenarios now the things
again enable the other side of that which is assistive technology?
Scenarios are built-in screenwriter how do you really help someone who
is blind interact or low-vision reed and interact with the data...on the screen.
There's some basic voice command control and
...windows speech recognition and use that same data
sonata click controls interact with controls nissan example
that third-party assistive technology to the toby eye tracking help
...work every day.
What is it that we kind of think about and own and work on every day and we work on that...layer work
...html layer work and making sure that your code as easy translate
...so that way enables net narration if
...voice command and control
third-party assistive technology so we run that entire gamut...spend everyday kind of think about how to make a better
and simpler for you to do that and today's talk focuses primarily
on screen reading because there's a large benefit that comes from doing this?
If you work through the api set
of problems space you end up helping do not only narrator but speech recognition
third-party apps there's a large amount of benefit gain throughout the entire system
...just to step back one second is that the narrative probably the best
demonstration of that protocol layer so bright talked about the ui automation system
...the fact that defines the protocol between all of the different
desperate ui frameworks and the various things that need to run on top of
...so narrator...speech recognition all these things...piped through
this ui automation layer so it gives this framework agnostic way of doing it so now you can have
...reading happen across your platform your app regardless of implementation technology
even if you build using some other thing like unity or something like this you can still
...through you adoration to allow all of these things to light up so,
even in cases where you don't necessarily think that there's a direct correlation to assistive
technology as you can get the benefit of screen reading from europe correct.
Really well of course things as...get of the time how do I held my every level read aloud the
brett how do I get my app to read aloud awesome question so today I really call it
what I'd consider to be as a narrator red-line everybody's written
...lines everybody sketched red-line...how to
...and really understand the transitions of their...has anyone here worked with a graphic
designer anyone yes great have you ever gotten a picture with little lines on...that said this
...be to pixels wide...should be this color...like rgb a...or in
...values that you that have to figure out the rgb value is an translate into a...say...
because they pick some pant on color all that craziness like...the designer red-line...the visual
...this pixel perfect manifestation of what your ui should look like and all those
...canvas step-by-step walked over ui...happen what are the color transitions so
that transition ability to take that same concept have a start state
a transition an and you'll see that and all of these are these red lines.
So, we're going to take a moment I'm going to focus on
...sketch...based on the...menu.
Now during windows eight
start many team arrived and said hey we want to put tiles on the start menu but I don't
want to do from accessibility...so I walked over.
...conference room and I said
...to me what it is...this is roughly the sketch and build.
I said...they mention will have tiles they could be square
they can be rectangle that could be really large squares...be small squares but they also
...a grid all right anything else yes they have names okay and they
have other data...news comes in I...bit about the news.
Awesome...just described all of...properties of...
idea we think we can do that but we're really worried about what it means to rearrange
I said okay we'll tell me what happens as well...put my finger down.
And, I start moving the item.
And, nothing really happens until I get to a certain state everything snaps.
...right so someone code you start...you can.
Summary start dragging a change visuals...visual changes
to put the new location let things and left in the right of it, you know, that code happens
...will yet...now you actually know everything you need to know to kind of put that from
a start transition and.
It turns out in this case it's just a drag drop pattern and you start.
...what happens in...
Let's take a lock through this.
Sort-of startup
narrator which how many people have ever launch narrator on their computer search
...awesome you...this is an for those of you haven't bringing
...narrator is most commonly done accidentally ...and by hitting windows
key enter your machine we'll start talking to you and you will not be able to figure out how to stop it and
...widely...on the keyboard to make it shut up and you'll figure out
...windows key enter will make it stop again one of the big changes we've been making we've been working hard
...narrator and making it a lot more what more
...lot faster and one of the things that we actually fixed a lot on was to make
startup and shutdown faster because when people started in there was a long delay they wouldn't correlate that
behavior...narrator here we put windows
key enter most narrator commands are access using the caps lock...and this what you do
special commands otherwise the normal keyboard shortcuts just continue to go through the program so
...selected the first item so let's see what narrator sets?
File explore...
...on selected...
So,...a bunch of information and error...said it was an item it said that it was a one of three so you
can see visually we can see...three things...must be talking about the top three things
...menu...what we arrow down and go to one of the tights in
visuals main grouped mail search, search.
Universities under pressure to divest...search.
You whether three of seven project spartan to of seven so you can
heroics pardon to of seven...everything things many times yes
...we can your narrative...information about where it is in the position
in the list so if you were user...to users you might want reorder the so you can get to the things you
...commonly early just because it's a grid of visual grid doesn't mean that a
non sighted person wouldn't care about where they go in this list and, it's
...courses drag...all its told us that it's ...it...tools to...we heard when it was
on search actually told us the live tile information all that can be read very easily to you and,
now we want to do that activity that we talked about in the what reader or the
walk through which was to rearrange the...so the keyboard
shortcut which I just learned about yesterday I didn't realize there was an awesome short-cut for this and I love
keyboard shortcuts so alt shift I believe all shift plus...and
then error...to allow you to drag-and-drop with your keyboard so let's start operation?
Drop to place...main before mail-in column three row
...now drop to place...between whether and calendar and column for row two so
...we heard that just for those of you are familiar with this we have slowed narrator down
...from what normal accessible users use it for so we can
kind of here but even then it's pretty fast so let's do one more time.
Drop to place...before mail-in column three row two so
...drop to place in main the name of the groups...place and main.
Row three column two I believe what...said between male and
whether so told us all of that information the to items to the side what position was
...the grid and what the name of the group what's the most contain forward into the next
...to place...main between male and whether in...row two and then...direct complete as
all of that information the dry complete all of that stuff that we talked about and it's really the
same way verbally you communicate like if I...please move one
...to your right you would know exactly what that what except we're facing differ
directions you be confused by the direction thing but,
no, one we confused what activity was or what I was asked me to do and
he said I've moved the...my right you'll understand that as well the big thing we find on
...lot of accessibility work is just getting people to think about it
as normal human communication and not some crazy
act inspector ui automation tree all
...stuff instead think about the output of the audible interface you want
...your program and basically if you're talking someone on the phone and to
prove this a little further let's just do this for a second and now we're going to see if we can all figure out what
Drop to place...before mail drop to place main between whether and calendar and column for
...to complete...everyone know what screens going to look like.
...at least one person nodding...paying attention that's good...two-fifty...
All right.
Great.
If we all thought it was between the whether encounter than we are right and we listened very carefully.
So, actually narrator.
...ability to take what you already know in your app to understand the
designed to be able to really walk through that narrator red-line
super important...to examples so chris has
a download research on some colors.
Yet...read x...is a great web...at least one person so x
...did this you do...interesting thing on the science the science of a
colors and what people think different colors are so he did a survey
...gettingtwo hundred-thousand people to respond on what they defined color...to be was
is very interesting if you crowd source your list of colors the names that you get back?
So, I want to do a little a web...that allows me to browser that list of colors and select one ...
using a pattern that we found that people often have
troubles with on the web which kind of these rich list the kinds of things.
So, as you type...expectation is the...kind
of narrows down you can go down and select that list by pressing enter on it we see
...quite often and in some cases as things happen on the
screen you might have location...tell people information the number of colors...really translator
things such as in mail apps or things where you think there's always this bad somewhere that
says loading and sinking and...kinda go through that and see what looks like, yeah, so, we built
...all sketch the...go through this and we did that same that thing that...lines experience and
we have our app you so I can see my colors I can select some we can go look
...I...this...box and go through select and item we can see,
you know, it turns out that if you ask a large population of people you'll come
up with a statistically significant selection of vomit oriented colors.
All right so,...try to scenarios do.
Http slash local host three thousand slash internet explorer window
Let's type...jelly.
Right why number eight zero three four group...so,...not read a lot of
we asked to we wanted to read the lot number of items the list as
...which I can actually see I have magnify...windows awesome
...right here that says how many...selected but we didn't read it and,
then ave flexing item if sense...slash local host three...luncheon
injured explore...http slash local host three thousand slash
raping number...to...fifty-five group...group.
Group is that what really have yes I...a list item
sitting narrator so let's start with fixing the number okay great because one of
these happens visually...typing this shrinks and that's significant because how many things do you want to
look through well if you can't see that do not that list is narrowing to something you might want to go
...picking through and looking at so let's talk about the large amount of code it takes to
do this great so this is my little app I did this using
the most tacking techniques I could think of that web...known to do so I'm degenerating a big
...string of gives an in whatever time
...update the display based on the thing I simply go through and grab all the colors I string can
...them...and I'm blast...into my inner html this is also perfect
perfectly...quite accessible...so let's see so,
we want to read that text every other change which we've got this one attacks...here which says hey
...text content equals the cullen you so one simple
thing...property great.
...alive equals polite so here is our summary element and
...daschle.
Because we like politeness...being rude yes we'll save that.
Go back and refresh...overwork and wellness
http end-of-life six hundred and seventy two of nine hundred and forty nine
mesh three hundred and nine of nine hundred and forty nine...fifty.
Read six of nine hundred and forty nine mesh awesome so
now the screener consumer completely no than down
to reasonable number I can go in and start walking through and the selecting colors
...the most critical...is actually http slash local
...three thousand is...when you come in six of nine hundred and forty nine
match zero of nine hundred and forty nine mesh
...ones when you get to nothing in the list correct and now I know there's nothing in
...the three exiting narrator all right?
So,...the next thing which in fact we said that wasn't reading the right thing on each
...correct so we probably like the
...a list item but so why is it saying group.
...just automatically transitioned into a group great...I
...it visually list I spent the time to like I added keyboard
...and I was a good web devon
made the right thing and it still wasn't quite right does not cleric of the doesn't know that is a list I.
What are the next?
Career list item great so this big blob of html
...here lovely you guessing and have to add more attributes you can have another attribute
...and ari role?
Now if you haven't done a lot of web development
there's a key thing going on here for dave's to turn them into accessibility is res.
Thanks...what...role you
...general equals.
Okay.
That...let's start with that run it.
Http a http.
Slash local host three thousand slash a zero percent vertically scroll
...pascal...number fifty six eighty fifty-seven.
Illnesses group one research group as beautiful we're closer
...probably like to know what number I'm on because...visually easy to see
zero yes that I'm on I'm on number four number
two number three so let's go ahead and put in the number.
Ok, so, that's a given...
Pauses in set.
And, set size.
...set...the overall set size so what's your an of m
...have the index.
For their and then.
We need to have the res...he said was deposited insets so...we just go and
Total count.
Skr http end-of-life.
Cloudy blue number ecc to...pascal
...number fifty six eighty fifty-seven I know why that's not really
do you...box yes.
Hilltop so list just like if you think about if you're familiar example or
html you have this notion of kind of container elements so you have a list boxer list items inside
...people accessibility needs no both piece of information as well as the case of this we have
...which we just have lots of diums like...html everything
...do and we told the excessively system that we had...items
...analyst by...not tell...was list box let's go and fix that...go here to the index
html safer are color slacks will say role equals.
List box.
Okay, and,...go try that skr
...http slash local host three thousand slash
...number btwenty nine-ninety sixty two of nine hundred and forty nine...the
non select awesome so, we get a two-for-one deal six a...a list...analyst item.
And, then by default and says okay...must not be selected but doesn't tell us if
it selected it's not that...this one is clearly deflecting sixty fifty seven.
Forty-nine non selected okay right so we close career we're getting close.
So, now if you go back and do another property for when it selected
...we are a selected equals true ok so here's?
The mobile html code so in this I have a event and
...is what I want to tag deflected...adding the selected css style.
Which shouldn't that be enough?
...know I could point ok
...so let's go addison so here we're trying to remove it...I believe we want
to set attribute.
...a selected.
And, then down here when we selected.
Will simply say the element we're going to insets like to
equal true awesome the right that's...illustrator?
...number nine hundred and ninety seven thousand five hundred and seventy
zero selected reddish grain...one number
...erode selected...zero three four so
now exiting narrator hunch code was this
let's look so this was a lot of code it was pretty painful let's look at
So, here's the total...we have.
So, we added three lines of code
...markup and these two function calls to
...selected and we made one other change which was to add the ari alive and
the...about total of six changes to make that pretty accessible that's a nice thing when folks
...walk through it really what we do we looked at the app dissected the
image...through it and one of the visual things are going on in the app at that time
...walk through...few pieces of mark-up and...good.
Well, there's a second set of things that we see
folks commonly do and that is that they love to have groups.
Of things and you don't really know.
When transitions happen so today if you think about
...such as music apps and video apps and loading things across the web there's
always larger level set and you click on it reuse list boxy load
a bunch of stuff may take a while and then either have one or more things that show up?
So, in this again we have
...here's...top-level list a sets.
And,...loading who knows what it's doing during that load.
And, then we get to the end there maybe one or more things there.
So, thank you built pretty much the same app, yeah, based on a color selection.
So, here instead of using html woodside you...show this behavior and, this is
...like...the very common pattern we see people reusing the list box in this case I'm
...have a set of colors we go and we can drill into one of these
and social all the colors that map...to that color so,
here we can see three things that are that sorry...couplings...this color and we go
to different color we have do ...have a few other things and,
each case what I've done to simulate the common pattern we see people kind of get messed up and we have
...delay between each one of these screens so,
if we look we're going to let's see what behavior we get by default out of
sample because now we have a real list hopefully...a little better oltre
...read system dark purple system dot elections dot generic dot
...herbal...light-blue
...system dot elections dot generic...teal that's is from dot how monthly
...that part of what if we go in here...one more things...case we navigated
...now we're sitting in the back we didn't hear I...know there was loading hopefuls it I
...know where focus went which?
...have the same process.
So, what happens in this case is that
again you look at the start state loading happens loading finishes and
...really knows kind of what happened so we've got a couple things to fix yep what we
want to go out...area however that we're naming let's give the naming first?
Just side effect where sometimes you get the classed name added to your overall name and that's
...useful what we did we did most of them...a really smart languages
it takes whatever data item you put into a list view it uses that...the...gels to
...now that works out great until the object you get is something like a.
A key value...
The generic collection which is what some idea
...this example very easy to do so in that case to string of a key value
...reads the classing which is very not useful so let's fix that.
So, in we've added events to grid view which lets you know,
when the content for containers changing...go to that event?
And, we'll go in and implement this with our new code.
Instead of throwing exception.
...a up moi what.
This does if we have two types of items in
our list we have either the top-level things which are these key value...or we have the lower-level
things which are individual colors since I'm reusing the same grid view for the items
...use a template selector which...familiar with...model...selector what
you choose between different views in this code I'm just going to look at the data type of the
...the term...I need to do so the important call here is automation properties that set
name and this allows me to control the name...going to be read for this basically when this
thing gets activated what you want narrator to speak so, it's really easy to go
set this property using our data model as we can push that in once you have a fixes.
So, now hopefully if we do right we will hear good it's much better...esri
...one of twenty-seven...selected so...the
rest of the...by the...listing the number of items that are in
there is listing the color name like and all that stuff came for free the
selection all that's...by default you get a pretty good experience you just need to figure out
these little details to go tweak exactly exiting...now the nice thing here.
...the...space it was rf and in the vema cases automation peers.
...properties, properties...yes thank you.
All right so,
we saw a couple of things we didn't get which was ...the.
Traditions.
Opposite yes.
To that let's notify people about what's going on so many click it
...toutes know that...loading
...waiting for infinity and the least to give them an idea of what's going on.
So, we did this html we use the...live region feature which
allowed us to have a little text area that we said hey every time we change that we want you to go read this to the
user so they know what...a similar thing here in the geometry soldiers...I'm going to go
...somewhere in the tree pretty much almost can be anywhere...put this element...so,
we just want to text...that can...blog at...
And, then we'll say we want to have it have a automation properties dot
Setting is...similar what we did before.
What other important thing we should do here because we already have a progress
indicator for those pesky sighted people who can see the screen yes having a
duplicate of text area we'll probably get their way yes so I think we should make this invisible
...yes but not collapsed not collapsed so...capacity zero
now it's important for those of you take note home to make the opacity zero not visibility
...visibly...takes it out the visual tree as will not be seen will not be
read will not participate in accessibility by making opacity zero it is invisible but
it is processed so in this case we can use this to trigger the narrator to read the right thing?
Great so now we just need to have a little function that's
...right function.
Of the work for taking over okay great.
...going to say a function called voidupdates.
just taken the message insource a reader dot text equals the message we want to say.
Lovely perfect and we have one lastly to do so that automation properties
...this and,...loves control.
Html like makes lots of decisions for you is totally dynamic it's the whole
hippie free...go whack on things the magically happen example we said we want
you control we don't want every time it has something to change want you to go in and have control over when this
happens so we need tells animal...now we want you to read...go notify the user so,
I think we do this with this awesome line of code which is framework element automation
The automation ps.
And,...say from element of the reader and
...say what we need to hear.
From the...that...very good thank you...
That...say the.
So, the framework automation peer.
Is this is that implementation
...we talked about ui automation...you have this protocol to control with the
screwed or does example they have a set of classes called for automation
peers and for every element you see on the screen there...automation peer behind-the-scenes and if you
...custom control you actually create your own automation peer the can do anything you want you-can
...to accessibility glider screener but you can also do cool things like you
can omit things from the automation api such...you can say
I have like thirty levels of nested crud in my visual tree but I don't want any
that to show up when people read it so I want you to jump down to this nested element inside turned
...or if...building full custom canvases you do all your own dtwo
...rendering you can also then make enable that...animation...well screeners can
reddit regardless of whether it's a full custom control or we're just modifying a
common control awesome so here we have where we put that busy way is active which this is the
...so here we want to say...say something right update reader just loading
...your data is looking?
The here shortly.
Come a long sentence.
But, we've got time.
And, I felt like I need to express my creativity all right so we've had
...say something...you see what happens.
So, hooked up the
...again a text...to look at and...what to say.
Color tree black one of...green three of
...back button your data will be here shortly.
Okay, we're close I don't know my data accurate exactly going to say that we
started we now the data is on its way but we don't really know
what happened so common people ask will do any...tell you that the
...loaded donated change that message in fact answer really is no we just
want to put them right on the first option so let's set focus...okay
great tool to color tree microsoft visual let's not have.
Narrator read all of my code.
Okay, now remember that's that line of code that was
robots taking over that is now the right thing to do the robot should take over right now.
So, let me explain what this does if we have some items in the grid view we want to restore focus to
that first item now if you're using example in a
mode where you're actually doing trues animal navigation between pages example grid view
does the right thing it sets...focus to the right element it puts the right thing in restores focus
the last thing it hasn't journal for tracking the stuff however
the reason we're showing you this way is that we continue to see people who re-use their
list because there's actually some performance benefits of taking the same list...it again and again...you
...this way example just doesn't know what to do it's not going
to steal focus from your app so it's not going to do...by default so,... how to take on some of this
bird is a case where even as a sighted user the fact that my focus was getting kind of
...that back button as a keyboard user would be pretty annoying eventually learn that every time you
could enter to go into something I have hit tab but even more frustrating tonon...user especially
...narrator just doesn't...correct so what we do here is I scroll interview the
item that was selected that was last selected or that we want to show I update the layout
...forces synchronous layout of the grid view so this forces the containers to be
realized that we have a real example element which we can then go and grab and
set focus to the reason...and programmatic is so that if the
users not using the keyboard they won't see the dotted lines the...appear around
the element so, we've done...I think we're good rights...share...
...chris was talking about is...if you had a tab into it and restart
to the list it just takes a long-time to get the to get through the same list
...hundred things long seven it's really hard electorate
...seven...it keeps it keeps talking...yeah, I know.
That's not so...your data will be your shortly.
...greek kelly green one of seven...also like
to perfect great...your data will be here short.
Green three of...I...to go to one of the that is these little shaded
...designer something secret about my code because I wrote which is anyone that have this
little cool gradient actually has no colors and let's see what happens?
Your data will be here shortly.
My data there yet I'm not looking at...are still waiting yes the
...still waiting I don't think it's coming okay I...is coming now what do I do so there's one
other interesting...handle zero case yes zero case.
So, before we had that...progress guy that was great so here we're going
...code just update that function call...say hey.
...you...account equals zero...actually have narrative
...update reader will say no item.
...the last case right perfectly run.
Culturally marine.
Light-blue...back button your data will be here shortly.
No, items.
...possible.
So, now everything is visual exiting narrator comes
...honorably and again who...talking again let's go look at that.
Cycled nineteen explore window.
Will do this old fashion way?
We added one-line here.
And, here we added.
Fifteen-minute many.
Convert from relatively inaccessible to...we want exactly
Interesting to can run that was magnify around once.
So, the...
we made earlier that by really helping self-tuning problems you actually help other system technologies.
Ok, can everyone see the back now?
Color tree...one of seven...selected back
...your data will be your shortly.
...button green dark blue dark teal a of
...back button your data will be here shortly.
Dark blue-green...back button and then
...shortly navigation to-you teal a of...
Non selected exiting
narrator so again by looking at that nice narrow slice of highly screeners work
you get the benefit now of magnify or tracking focus
again resumed in if you didn't have that had to look that long list and with the magnify around
...lost it's hard-to-find a place again so really a little bit of work and narrator goes along
...helping people magnification and other systems technologies.
So, kind of a golda davis do, you know,
how to walk to your app now think about each step think about the start state the transition
and the end as you can see really from html
silos about six lines of code, for example,...
was about fifteen sixteen lines of code and from something is not usable
...useful by screenwriter very short amount of lines of code again html world
...ariel really helps...be decker in a way that can be accessible...automation
peers and automation properties...used to help make...be accessible?
And, then from doing that.
Again,
all of this goes across all the windows universal platform on a mobile device for the desktop you're
going to get that same experience eone and there's a couple links down here really about
...get more information is developer and the to links to thesource code is
actress work on today you look at the to projects there's a branch which is the
demo start branch and there's a branch that's master which is the final version that has everything
workings you can look at those two and see what we had to change.
Thank you very much yes...questions
...have time for questions...for...if you want to go to the microphone if anybody has questions
...to things let us know think there's a microphone they're over there.
...catches...we're going to be in the
windows insider lunge windows insider lounge the next ninety minutes so if you have any question about anything yes.
Do we know anything about the ability accessibility group and...
Okay, great moi.
Yeah, so, the question was
we aware of the and vp group around accessibility microsoft and the answer is I guess we
are definitely that they would be interested information...thanks.